nero.com 2009-03-16

# Nero - Privacy

Since your privacy is important to us, Nero AG has created this privacy statement in order to let you know our firm commitment to your privacy.

  1. **Our Websites**
  2. **Nero 8 and future versions software suite**

## 1\. Our websites

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Nero AG group of websites which include:

  * nero.com
  * ahead.de
  * nerodigital.com

### Information collection

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you ("Personal Information") or allows us to contact you. Generally this information is requested when you register for an online service, or you want to provide us with your personal data, to give us the opportunity to get in touch with you.  
When you enter a contest or other promotional event, we may ask for information such as your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address so we can administer the contest and notify winners.  
When you register, we may ask you for information such as your name, e-mail address, shipping address, and serial number.  
We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and your time spent at our sites, and to gather broad demographic information. This allows us to see which parts of our sites users are visiting. We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means, for instance, that a user's session will be tracked, but the user will remain anonymous. We do not use this information for any other puposes.  
When a user submits personal information, it is kept on a private server not accessible from the Internet. This limits the possibility of any malicious use of your information.  
Visitors can change or correct information about themselves via our registration system. If there is a problem with a change being accepted by our system, you may contact us at the e-mail address: [webmaster@nero.com](mailto:webmaster@nero.com)  
If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use most of our websites anonymously. But you will not be able to access areas that require registration. Only the domain name from which you access the Internet, the Internet address and the date and time you access our web sites are logged. Nero AG uses this information to analyze trends and to measure the number of visitors to our web sites.

### Use of personal information

Nero AG may share non-personal, summary information regarding its customers with partners or other third parties. However, for partners or third parties under contract with Nero AG, any individual customer information provided may be used solely to perform or complete a necessary transaction or function related to the customer's purchase. These transactions or functions shall be in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy Statement. Nero AG will not share any individual customer information outside of the contracted partners and third parties mentioned above, without first receiving the individual's prior written approval. In short, Nero AG does not sell registrant information to lists. In some cases, Nero AG may use a visitor's personal information to understand overall patterns for site usage, to contact the user for clarification on inaccurate information, or to follow up on a customer service issue. Personal information may include name, address, telephone number, etc.

### Opt-Out policy

When a visitor registers, the visitor will be given the opportunity to select whether or not to be included on the Nero AG mailing list. Inclusion on the mailing list may entitle the user to receive information or updates about special offers, programs, new products and/or services. Choosing not to register means the user will not be able to receive these benefits or this information.

### Links to other sites

This site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Nero AG is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web Sites as well as any information they might collect, even though our name or logo may appear on those sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the Privacy Statements of each and every Web site that you visit, as the privacy policy of those sites may differ from ours. Our Privacy Statement applies solely to [www.nero.com](http://www.nero.com/)

### Use of “cookies”

During your visit to our website, so-called “cookies” are saved to your computer. These “cookies” register information about the navigation of your computer on our website (loaded pages, date, time of day and length of visit etc.) which we can access during your next visit in order to adapt the website to your personal requirements and optimize loading times. We also use this information to enter your data into enquiry forms and suchlike so that you do not need to fill them in yourself again and again.  
We never store passwords or similarly sensitive data in cookies.  
The use of cookies is common and advantageous. Cookies are used on most larger websites. By indicating how and when visitors use a website, cookies aid us in finding out which areas are popular and which areas are not. Many improvements and updates are based on information supplied by cookies. Cookies can also help us to personalize web content and meet the desires of our visitors.  
Our websites do not use cookies to collect personal information from your computer that was not initially sent as a cookie.  
You have the option to control the acceptance of cookies yourself and, if you wish, to block them entirely by configuring your browser as follows:  
If you use the Internet Explorer to surf the net: In the “Tools” menu, click “Internet Options”, select the “Privacy” tab and click “Advanced”. Here, you can “Block” cookies or set up a “Prompt”. The latter setting allows you to decide from occasion to occasion whether you would like to accept a cookie or not.

## 2\. Nero 8 and future versions software suite

### Information collection

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Nero AG software suite Nero 8.  
**a) Registration**  
We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you ("Personal Information") or allows us to contact you. Generally this information is requested when you register your copy of the Nero 8 software suite.  
When you register your copy of the Nero 8 software suite, we will ask in the user registration dialog for some personal data including, but not limited to your First Name and Last Name, your e-mail address and your home country. During the registration process your personal Nero 8 serial number will be also submitted and the Nero internal version of the disc and software.

**b) Nero Improvement Program**  
During the installation of the software suite, the user will be given the opportunity to select, whether or not, to participate in the Nero Improvement Program. In the Nero Improvement Program, the user allows Nero to retrieve non-personal Nero application usage information from the users system, afterwards this information will be sent anonymously to a secure Nero server for analysis in order to further improve the Nero software suite. The following non-personal information is retrieved: **Name of the Product, Installed applications, version, time and date of installation, country (according to the settings of the operating system), version of operating system and the count of application starts. The data with the count of application starts will be sent anonymously to a secure Nero server, on a regular basis. The participation in this Nero Improvement Program can be cancelled at any time, by simply deactivating this service in the Nero ControlCenter.**

### Use of personal information

Nero AG may share non-personal, summary information regarding its customers with partners or other third parties. However, for partners or third parties under contract with Nero AG, any individual customer information provided shall be used only to perform or complete a necessary transaction or function related to the customer's purchase. These transactions or functions shall be in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy Statement. Nero AG will not share any individual customer information outside of the contracted partners and third parties mentioned above, without first receiving the individual's prior written approval. In short, Nero AG does not sell registrant information to lists. In some cases, Nero AG may use a user's personal information to understand overall patterns for software usage, to contact the user for clarification on inaccurate information, or to follow up on a customer service issue. Personal information may include name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, etc.

### Opt-Out policy

When a user registers, the user will be given the opportunity to select whether or not to be included in the Nero AG mailing list. Inclusion on the mailing list may entitle the user to receive information or updates about special offers, programs, new products and/or services.

**To help us improve our privacy policies, please give us your[feedback, comments and suggestions](mailto:webmaster@nero.com).**

### Updates and Changes to Privacy Statement

We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add, to change, update or modify this Privacy Statement, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the web site. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on the web site.
